Hi, I'm Natanya Nielsen from Saratoga Springs, Utah.
Today we're going to talk about crochet basics, and we're going to start with the chain stitch.
We start with a slip stitch.
To do your slip stitch, you're going to lay your yarn over top of your pinkie, wrap it around the back of your hand, and grasp it between your middle finger and your thumb.
Take your hook and lay it underneath your yarn.
Then you'll twist it all the way around, grab your yarn with your hook, and pull it through the loop.
Pull that loop tight, and you have your slip stitch.
To start your chain stitch, you're going to grab the yarn with the hook part of your crochet hook, then you'll pull that through the loop that's already on your hook.
And you will have another loop on your hook.
You do the same thing over and over again.
As your chain gets longer, simply slide your fingers towards your hook to help hold it stable, to help keep your stitches the same length.
You want to practice being loose and controlled and relaxed as you do this, because the looser your chain is, the easier it is to continue your project.